Church Materials from Guatemala, II, 1913-2001: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library
Church Materials from Guatemala, II
1913-2001
MICROFILM 12378
LAE003
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
6 microfilm reels
Princeton University. Library.
This microfilm contains pamphlet materials published by Christian groups in Guatemala between 1929 and 2001.
The Princeton University Library has developed numerous collections of Latin American ephemera that are unique in their depth and scope. Privileging the popular voices of the region, the collections document numerous political and social movements, and a wide variety of key socioeconomic and cultural developments. Some particularly well-documented topics are grassroots organizing, human rights, electoral politics, indigenous issues, women and gender issues, youth, the environment, health, education, and religion. Types of primary materials collected include pamphlets, non-commercially produced and distributed serials, flyers, posters, working papers, government publications, and other non-traditional formats. Most of the documentation in the collections was produced after the mid 1960s by Latin American nongovernmental organizations of all types, interest groups, political parties, research institutes, and government agencies.
The intensive collecting of ephemera was initiated by Barbara Hadley Stein, the University’s first Bibliographer for Latin America, Spain and Portugal (1966-1977). She sought to document some of the major political developments of the period, including the rise to power of military dictatorships, coup d’états, the institutionalization of the Cuban Revolution, and the popular responses to those developments. Her successor, Peter T. Johnson (1977-2003), expanded the geographic and thematic scope of the collections and systematized the process of organizing, cataloging, and preserving them. Intensive collecting in this area continues to this date.
Over the years, materials have been grouped and organized by country or region, and by topic or subject area. Once collections are fully organized, they are cataloged and microfilmed. A complete list of collections appears in the Guide to the Princeton University Latin American Microfilm Collection (Wilmington, DE: Scholarly Resources, 1993) and subsequent supplements. Many of the collections’ finding aids are available online. Original print materials have been preserved in many cases.
This microfilm contains pamphlet materials published by Christian groups in Guatemala between 1929 and 2001. The materials are divided into alphabetically arranged files according to subject. These subject divisions are not meant to be strict or definitive. They are merely a guideline for the researcher. Some pamphlets may fit just as well under one subject heading as another, and the materials in various files may overlap in scope.
The majority of the material in this microfilm is published by the Catholic Church. Much of it consists of essays on points of theological debate, the current state of the Church in Guatemala, or the Church's response to socio-economic issues. Of particular interest are several pamphlets about individual works of religious art or sculpture and the local traditions and rituals surrounding them (see File 7: History and File 13: Religious Art). The last file, File 19: Miscellaneous, should not be overlooked by the researcher. Though the pamphlets in this file could not be easily grouped under a single subject heading, they are no less interesting than the rest of the contents of the microfilm.
The materials are divided into alphabetically arranged files according to subject. Within each file, publications are arranged alphabetically by title.
The Latin American ephemera collections are open for research use.
Microfilm can be consulted in Microforms Service, Firestone Library (http://firestone.princeton.edu/microforms/).
Please consult with the Department of Rare Books and Special Collections about having those portions of the collection that are stored off site recalled to the Department for your use. This process normally requires 48-72 hours notice.
MICROFILM 7792 (Master printing copy. Available for reproduction only.)
Catholic Church -- Guatemala.; Church and social problems -- Guatemala.; Protestant churches -- Guatemala.; Religion and politics -- Guatemala.; Religious architecture -- Guatemala.; Religious art -- Guatemala.; Religious biography -- Guatemala.; Religious education -- Guatemala.; Latin American studies
- Biblical Figures and Concepts, 1997; File 1; 1 item
  - La cruz de Cristo. Juan Kessler. San José, Costa Rica: Instituto Internacional de Evangelización a Fondo (IINDEF), undated; 88p
  - Ella. Nuestra Señora del Sagrado Corazón, abogada de las causas difíciles y deseperadas. Joaquín Herrera Bayón. Guatemala: Misioneros del Sagrado Corazón (MSC), undated; 67p
  - Jesús de Nazaret, su tiempo y su proyecto. Fernando Bermúdez. Guatemala: Semilla de Esperanza, 1997; 32p
- Biographies of Church Figures, 1913-1998; File 2; 1 item
  - El Beato Hermano Pedro: en el X aniversario de su beatificación. Damián C. Muratori. Guatemala: s.n., 1991; 35p
  - Beato Hermano Pedro de San José de Betancour, T.F.: Carta Viva de Crista. José Francisco García Bauer. s.l.: s.n., undated; 27p
  - De los negocios al ministerio: testimonio personal de Samuel Berberian. Samuel Berberian. Guatemala: Ediciones SA-BER, 1993; 14p
  - Una flor de Xelajú. Josefina Oliva Mazariegos, Cecilia Teresa Vargas Méndez, et.al. Guatemala: Las Hermanas Bethlemitas, 1985; 39p
  - El Hermano Pedro, un hombre de Dios. Marta Pilon. Guatemala: Editorial Artemis & Edinter, 1996; 80p
  - La leyenda de Sor Angélica. Avelino F. Mariscal. Guatemala: Tipografía "América", 1934; 67p
  - Madre Encarnación Rosal, primera santa de Guatemala. Josefina Oliva Mazariegos. [Guatemala: Hermanas Bethlemitas], undated; 24p
  - Mártir de la Paz: Monseñor Juan Gerardi Conedera, 1922-1998. s.a. [Guatemala]: Oficina de Derechos Humanos del Arzobispado de Guatemala (ODHAG), 48p
  - Padre Guatemala: el misionero de Quetzaltenango. José Diaz Durán. Guatemala, C.A.: Talleres Gráficos de Editorial E. A. Galindo, 1979; 79p
  - Reseña biográfica del ilustrísimo y reverendísimo Señor Arzobispo de Santiago de Guatemala don Ricardo Casanova y Estrada. José M. Ramírez Colom. Guatemala: Tipografía Sánchez & De Guise, 1913; 95p
  - Santo Domingo de Guzmán y los Domínicos. [Fray Nelson D. Castillo Valle and Fray Héctor Manuel Araya Madrigal] Guatemala: [Padres Domínicos], undated; 22p
  - Tarzán López, domador de fieras. Alfonso Aurelio López Ochoa and Martha de Berberián. Guatemala, C.A.: Alfonso López and Ediciones SA-BER, 1985; 36p
  - Uaxactun. Guatemala: Editorial de Ministerio de Educación Pública, 1961 June 1; 1 item
    - Año I, no.1, 1961 June 1; 1 item
  - Vida del P. Fr. Domingo de Betanzos de la Orden de Santo Domingo. Juan Rodríguez Cabal. Guatemala: Tipografía Sánchez & De Guise, 1934; 84p
- The Church and Indigenous Peoples, 1987-1996; File 3; 1 item
  - Clamor y resurrección del Pueblo Maya. s.a. [Cobán]: Pastoral Indígena de Guatemala, 1992; 44p
  - El cofre: iniciación de los niños mayas en la vida cristiana. Carlos Berganza, Ed. Cobán: Ak' Kutan, Centro Bartolomé de las Casas, 1996; 57p
  - Documento sobre pastoral Indígena. s.a. Cobán: Conferencia Interprovincial Dominicos América Latina (CIDAL), 1988; 57p
    (Dossier CIDAL; 4)
  - Estos, sí son hombres: a propósito de Bartolomé de las Casas. Fernando Suazo and J. Amando Robles. Cobán: Ak' Kutan, Centro Bartolomé de las Casas, 1992; 76p
    (Textos Ak' Kutan;1)
  - La Iglesia y el movimiento indígena en Guatemala. Ivon le Bot. Jorge Luis Arriola, Trans. Guatemala: Seminario de Integración Social Guatemalteca, 1987; 37p
    (Cuadernos del Seminario de Integración Social Guatemalteca; sexta serie, no.31, 1987)
  - Memoria del primer encuentro de catequistas. s.a. Cobán: Pastoral Indígena de Guatemala, 1990; 75p
  - Plan nacional de pastoral indígena. s.a. Comisión Nacional de Pastoral Indígena de la CEG, 1995; 32p
  - Respetemos las canas y retoños del Pueblo Maya. Félix Lorenzo Velásquez Saquic. Guatemala: Saquil Tzij de PRODESSA, 1994; 98p
- The Church's Role in Society, 1961-1996; File 4; 1 item
  - Análisis de la participación política de los evangélicos en Guatemala. Vitalino Similox Salazar. Guatemala: Conferencia de Iglesias Evangélicas de Guatemala, 1993; 30p
  - Una caminata por la paz/Tun b'inem rech saq lianik k'aslemal. Marvin Sánchez and Mario Recancoj. Guatemala: Editorial Saqil Tzij and Escuela Superior de Educación Integral Rural (ESEDIR), 1996; 105p
  - Carta pastoral del excmo. y revmo. Sr. Dr. Constantino Luna y Pianegonda, Obispo de la Diócesis de Zacapa sobre los deberes cívicos del Católico. Constantino Luna y Pianegonda. [Zacapa]: s.n., 1961; 25p
  - El clamor por la tierra: carta pastoral colectiva del Episcopado Guatemalteco. Monseñor Próspero Penados del Barrio, Monseñor Rodolfo Quezada Toruño, et.al. Guatemala, C.A.: s.n., 1988; 28p
  - El clamor por la tierra, versión popular. s.a. [Guatemala, C.A.]: s.n., 1988; 29p
  - El compromiso del cristiano frente a los derechos humanos. Ramiro de León Carpio. Guatemala, C.A.: Editorial Cultura, 1995; 53p
  - Los cristianos frente al neoliberalismo. Fernando Bermúdez. Guatemala: Oficina de Derechos Humanos del Arzobispado de Guatemala, 1996 (Colección nueva presencia; 3), 1 item
  - Cristo muere y resucita en Guatemala. Fernando Bermúdez. Buenos Aires: Casa Unida de Publicaciones, S.A. (CUPSA), 1985; 68p
    (Voces Cristianas Latinoamericanas; no. 2)
  - Los cristianos de América Latina frente al neoliberalismo. s.a. Guatemala: Oficina de Derechos Humanos del Arzobispado de Guatemala, Departamento de Educación y Promoción, 1996; 64p
  - Los derechos humanos en las sagradas escrituras. Julio Aguilar. Guatemala: Oficina de Derechos Humanos del Arzobispado de Guatemala, 1993 (Colección nueva presencia; 1), 1 item
  - La Iglesia y los derechos humanos. José Álvarez Lobo Guatemala City: Editorial Lascasiana, undated; 47p
    (Colección pastoral)
  - "Ofensiva del pueblo": campesino contra campesino. s.a. s.l.: Iglesia Guatemalteca en el Exilio (IGE), 1989; 33p
  - El protestantismo en dos barrios marginales de Guatemala. Bryan Roberts. Guatemala: Seminario de Integración Social Guatemalteca, 1967; 22p
    (Estudios centroamericanos; no.2)
  - El pueblo como sujeto. Alternativas desde lo excluidos. Guatemala: Conferencia Interprovincial Dominicos América Latina (CIDAL), 1993; 60p
    (Dossier CIDAL 7)
  - Siete meditaciones sobre la paz: discurso pronunciado en la Catedral Metropolitana el 6 de enero de 1969. Carlos Martínez Duran. Guatemala: Editorial "José de Pineda Ibarra", 21p
  - ¡Urge la verdadera paz! s.a. s.l.: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala (CEG), undated; 80p
  - Valores y reingeniería de los partidos demócrata cristianos. Miguel Ángel Rodríguez E. Ciudad de Guatemala: Instituto Centroamericano de Estudios Políticos (INCEP), 1995; 86p
    (Ensayos socialcristianos; 3)
  - Series: Doctrina social de la Iglesia, published by the Instituto de Enseñanza para el Desarrollo Sostenible, dates not examined; 1 item
    - Centesimus annus y capitalismo. Ramón Rodríguez Paradela. Guatemala, C.A.: Instituto de Enseñanza para el Desarrollo Sostenible (IEPADES), undated; 34p
      (Doctrina social de la Iglesia; 1)
    - El cristiano y la política. Ramón Rodríguez Paradela. Guatemala, C.A.: Instituto de Enseñanza para el Desarrollo Sostenible (IEPADES), undated; 35p
      (Doctrina social de la Iglesia; 2)
    - Fuentes y bases de la doctrina social de la Iglesia. Ramón Rodríguez Paradela. Guatemala, C.A.: Instituto de Enseñanza para el Desarrollo Sostenible (IEPADES), undated; 48p
      (Doctrina social de la Iglesia; 3)
    - Persona y sociedad en doctrina social de la Iglesia. Ramón Rodríguez Paradela. Guatemala, C.A.: Instituto de Enseñanza para el Desarrollo Sostenible (IEPADES), undated; 36p
      (Doctrina social de la Iglesia; 4)
- The Eucharist, 1964-1996; File 5; 1 item
  - Comunión en la mano. s.a. Guatemala: Comisión de Liturgia de la Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1991; 16p
  - La divina Eucaristía a través de la historia. Manuel Coronado Aguilar. Guatemala: Editorial del Ejército, 1964; 39p
  - Espíritu Santo eucarístico. Sebastiano Crestani. Guatemala: s.n., 1996; 51p
  - Eucaristía con niños: plegarias eucarísticas. s.a. Guatemala: Centro Salesiano de Pastoral Juvenil, 1995; 41p
- Evangelization, 1992-2001 August; File 6; 1 item
  - 500 años sembrando el Evangelio: carta pastoral colectiva de los obispos de Guatemala. s.a. Guatemala: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala (CEG), 1992; 64p
  - Inculturación: nuevo rostro de la Iglesia. Domingo Salado and Jesús Tapuerca. Coban: Ak' Kutan, Centro Bartolomé de las Casas, 1996; 79p
    (Textos Ak' Kutan; 5)
  - Proclamando a Jesús entre los pueblos no alcanzados. Guatemala: Dirección Nacional de Misiones y Evangelismo, Iglesia de Dios Evangelio Completo de Guatemala, 2001 June-August; 1 item
    - Vol.1, no.1, 2001 June-August; 1 item
  - Reflexiones finales sobre la cultura y la inculturación de la fe, según la carta 500 años sembrando el evangelio. Víctor Hugo Martínez Contreras. Guatemala: Diócesis de Los Altos, Quetzaltenango, 1995; 24p
- History, 1968-1999; File 7; 1 item
  (see also File 10: Mass, Prayers, and Other Rituals)
  - El año ritual de la Nía Chabela ... transcurrido en la Nueva Guatemala de la Asunción. Miguel Álvarez Arévalo. Guatemala: Fondo Editorial "La Luz", undated; 55p
  - Guía del Convento de Capuchinas de Antigua Guatemala. Jorge Luján Muñoz. Guatemala: Consejo Nacional para la Protección de la Antigua Guatemala, 1991; 46p
  - Historia de la Iglesia Santo Domingo de Guatemala. Fray Juan Rodríguez Cabal and Fray Luis María Estrada Paetau. Guatemala: Convento Santo Domingo, 1993; 61p
  - Informe sobre el estado de conservación de las iglesias de Antigua Guatemala y algunas medidas para su preservación. John E. Hibbitts. [Guatemala]: Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala, 1968; 66p
  - El orígen del Catolicismo Romano en la Bíblia y en la historia, refutando los errores de los evangélicos. Calixto Senica. Segunda Edición. Patulul: Escuela Parroquial La Inmaculada, 1988; 63p
  - Orígen, erección y fundación de la Hermandad de la Vírgen del Rosario. Francisco José Cajas Ovando. Quetzaltenango: El Estudiante, 1989; 11p
    (Colección Quetzaltenango; Volúmen VI)
  - Testamento y título de los antecesores de los Señores de Cagcoh San Cristóbal Verapaz. Alejandra Colom, Alfredo Maul, et.al. Guatemala, C.A.: Universidad del Valle de Guatemala, 1999; 23p
- Internal Church Publications: Bulletins, Conferences, Letters, 1929-2000; File 8; 1 item
  - Annual Report 1999. s.a. Guatemala: CEDEPCA, 34p
  - Boletín eclesiastico de la Arquidiócesis de Guatemala. Guatemala: Arzobispado de Guatemala, dates not examined; 1 item
    - no.96 (noviembre y diciembre 1989), dates not examined; 1 item
    - no.98 (marzo y abril 1990), dates not examined; 1 item
    - no.106 (octubre-diciembre 1991), dates not examined; 1 item
  - Boletín de teología y pastoral. Guatemala: Instituto de Teología, 1993; 1 item
    - Año 1, no.1, 1993; 1 item
  - Caritas Arquidiocesana. s.a. Guatemala: Arzobispado de Guatemala, 1981; 22p
  - Carta pastoral del Arzobispo Monseñor Mariano Rossell y Arellano. Mariano Rossell y Arellano. [Guatemala]: s.n., 1954; 13p
  - Carta pastoral del excelentísimo y reverendísimo Señor Don Luis Durou y Sure, C.M., Arzobispo de Guatemala y Administrador Apostólico de Verapaz y Petén con motivo del próximo Congreso Eucarístico Internacional. s.a. Guatemala: [Tipografía Sánchez & De Guise], undated; 8p
  - Directorio de la Arquidiócesis de Guatemala. s.a. Guatemala: Arzobispado de Guatemala, 1989-2000; 36p
    - 1989, 1991, 1993, 1994, 1995, 2000, 1 item
  - Directorio eclesiástico. s.a. Guatemala: s.n., 1988; 58p
  - En camino hacia el 2000. Plan global de la Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala 1997-2000. s.a. s.l.: Ediciones San Pablo, 48p
  - Exposición del ceremonial para la consagración de los obispos. s.a. Guatemala: [Tipografía Sánchez & De Guise, ], 1929; 23p
  - Jesucristo ayer, hoy y siempre. s.a. Guatemala de la Asunción: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1997; 32p
  - "Juntos en acción misional en la década del 90." Encuentro Metodista. s.a. Antigua, Guatemala: s.n., 1991; 14p
- Marriage and Family, 1994-1998; File 9; 1 item
  (see also File 16: Religious Study and Education)
  - Arzobispado Primado de Guatemala: Pastoral Familiar de Casos Especiales. s.a. Guatemala: Arquidiócesis Primada de Guatemala, 1998; 48p
  - La familia cristiana, agente primordial de la nueva evangelización. Prospero Penados del Barrio. Guatemala: s.n., 1994; 23p
  - Matrimonio Eucaristico. Crestani Sebastiano. Guatemala: s.n., 1994; 44p
- Mass, Prayers, and Other Rituals, 1932-1994; File 10; 1 item
  (see also File 7: History, File 16: Religious Study and Education)
  - Amorosa visita y adiós vespertino a Jesús sacramentado: recuerdo de mis bodas de plata sacerdotales. Julio Martínez Flores. Guatemala: [Tipografía Sánchez y De Guise], 1932; 8p
  - Ejercicio de las Diez Lámparas. Madre Encarnación Rosal. s.l.: s.n., undated; 16p
  - Estampas tradicionales de Cuaresma en la Antigua Guatemala. Carlos Alfredo Navas Solares. Guatemala: Fondo Editorial Santiago de Guatemala, 1994; 52p
  - Nuestra Semana Santa. Roberto Vásquez Lorenzana. Guatemala, C.A.: Ethos Comunicación, 1994; 29p
  - Procesiones '94: recorridos, horarios, historia. s.a. Guatemala: Impresos Caudal, 1994; 19p
  - Recuerdo: jaculatorias y súplicas al Divino Corazón de Jesús. s.a. [Antigua Guatemala: Talleres Torres Sucs.], undated; 4p
  - Semana Santa en la Antigua Guatemala. Carlos Humberto Quintanilla Meza. Guatemala, C.A.: Consejo Nacional Para la Protección de la Antigua Guatemala, 1989; 28p
  - Sembrador: manual de espiritualidad del evangelizador. José María Vigil. Guatemala: Editorial Lascasiana, 1993; 90p
- The Modern Church, 1986-1998; File 11; 1 item
  - Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala. Instrucción pastoral colectiva de los Obispos de Guatemala sobre la renovación carismática. s.a. Guatemala: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1986; 20p
  - La hora de los laicos: su misión en la Iglesia. Fernando A. Bermúdez López. s.l.: Arzobispado de Guatemala, undated; 52p
  - Iglesia universal, iglesias particulares. Coban: Ak' Kutan, Centro Bartolomé de las Casas, 1998; 88p
    (Textos Ak' Kutan; 13)
  - El pueblo de Dios (eclesiología). s.a. Guatemala: Arquidiócesis de Guatemala, 1990; 124p
- The Pope, 1971-1996; File 12; 1 item
  - Algunas reflexiones sobre la centesimus annus, o, la centenaria, encíclica de Juan Pablo II. Pope John Paul II. Guatemala City: Asociación de Investigación y Estudios Sociales (ASIES), 1992; 23p
  - Carta apostólica de Su Santidad el Papa Pablo VI al Señor Cardenal Mauricio Roy. Pope Paul VI. Guatemala: s.n., 1971; 39p
  - Carta encíclica de Su Santidad el Papa Pablo VI sobre el desarrollo de los pueblos. Pope Paul VI. Guatemala: Cortesía de los Cursillos de Cristiandad de la Arquidiócesis de Guatemala, undated; 60p
  - Centenario de la encíclica Rerum Novarum. s.a. s.l.: Departamento de Investigaciones Económicas y Sociales, undated; 34p
  - Mensajes del Papa Juan Pablo II en su segunda visita a Guatemala, Nicaragua y El Salvador. Pope John Paul II. Guatemala City: Ediciones San Pablo, 1996; 56p
  - El papa y el evangelio: discurso pronunciado en el Concilio Vaticano por el Obispo Strossmayer. Bishop Strossmayer. Quezaltenango: Tipográfico "El Noticiero Evangélico", undated; 19p
  - Recuerdo de la misión de paz de Su Santidad Juan Pablo II durante su visita a la tierra de los Mayas. Diego Molina. Guatemala: [SFI/DMF], 1983; 30p
  - Los representantes pontificios. s.a. [Guatemala]: s.n., undated; 12p
- Religious Art, 1978-1997; File 13; 1 item
  - "Consagración" de la imagen del Cristo Yacente, Basílica de Nuestra Señora del Rosario, Templo de Santo Domingo. José Luis Barrios Quiñónez. s.l.: s.n., undated; 63p
  - Hace cuatro siglos: las romerías y tradiciones de Esquipulas. Terry Bond and Oscar Horst. s.l.: s.n., 1995; 18p
  - Jesús de la Merced de Panchoy a la Ermita, 1655-1778. Miguel Álvarez Arévalo. Guatemala: Fondo Editorial La Luz, 1997; 42p
    (Colección imágenes de Guatemala; Vol.II)
  - Jesús Nazareno de los Milagros en la Nueva Guatemala de la Asunción. Miguel Álvarez Arévalo. Guatemala: Asociación de Jesús Nazareno de los Milagros, 1978; 24p
  - El Señor Sepultado de Santo Domingo. Federico Alfredo Prahl Redondo. Nueva Guatemala de la Asunción: Instituto de Investigaciones Históricas Antropológicas y Arqueológicas, 1997; 89p
    (Aportes a la historia del arte; no.1, 1997)
- Religious Music, 1985; File 14; 1 item
  - 37 cantos misioneros vocacionales y otros juveniles. s.a. s.l.: [Misioneros Combonianos del Corazón de Jesus], undated; 15p
    (Cantos sin fronteras; no.4)
  - ¡Excelencia! Album de coros. Jaime Adolfo Gamboa Campos, Vilma M. Quan de García, et.al. Guatemala: Ministerio "Beraca", undated; 57p
  - Música en su alma: la historia del músico y evangelita guatemalteco Alfredo Colom. Alfredo Colom M. Guatemala: Ediciones SA-BER, 1985; 18p
- Religious Poetry, 1993-1996; File 15; 1 item
  - Perfume de lirio: poesía lírica evangélica. Délfido Barrera Navas. Guatemala: Fondo de Cultura Editorial, 1993; 95p
  - ¿Quién eres, tú, mujer?: lírica en alabanza a Jesucristo. Victor M. Rivas. Guatemala: s.n., 1996; 22p
- Religious Study and Education, 1952-1999; File 16; 1 item
  (see also File 10: Mass, Prayers, and other Rituals)
  - XXXVI Jornada Mundial de Oración por las Vocaciones, 1999. s.a. Guatemala: Centro Nacional de Pastoral Vocacional, 72p
  - A.B.C. de la temperancia: lecciones sobre las bebidas embriagantes. Pablo Burgess. Tercera Edición. Quetzaltenango: El Noticiero Evangélico, 1952; 67p
  - El apocalípsis: guía para su estudio en comunidad. Fernando A. Bermúdez López. Guatemala: Arzobispado de Guatemala, undated; 55p
  - Celebramos la buena noticia de Jesús. s.a. Quetzaltenango: Arquidiócesis de Quetzaltenango, 1997; 98p
    (Celebraciones de la palabra de Dios, Ciclo B; 2a parte: Cuaresma, Semana Santa, Pascua)
  - Cuatro milenios de la educación religiosa: historia de la educación cristiana. Martha Saint de Berberián. Guatemala: Ediciones SA-BER, 1986; 44p
  - La educación en el magisterio de la Iglesia. s.a. Guatemala: Comisión de Educación de la Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1994; 96p
  - Escucha la palabra: lectio divino para la liturgia dominical. s.a. Ciudad Guatemala: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1993; 20p
    (Año Litúrgico "A", Tiempo de Cuaresma)
  - Escucha la palabra: lectio divino para la liturgia dominical y festiva. s.a. Ciudad Guatemala: Conferencia Episcopal de Guatemala, 1994; 24p
    (Año Litúrgico "B", Solemnidad: la transfiguración del Señor)
  - Historia de la salvación: curso bíblico popular. Flaviano Amatulli Valente. [Guatemala: Apóstoles de la Palabra, ], 1992; 48p
  - "Iré y le curaré": manual de pastoral de enfermos. José María Vigil. Second Edition. s.l.: Editorial Lascasiana, undated; 65p
  - Raíces > nueva cultura: temas para reflexión teológica. Ricardo Bendaña Perdomo. Guatemala: Universidad Rafael Landívar, 1995; 89p
  - Sacramentos como vida y compromiso. Álvaro Quevedo. Second Edition. Quetzaltenango: Arquidiócesis de Quetzaltenango, 1996; 66p
  - Todos hermanos: iniciación cristiana para niños. Para ser trabajada con la familia. Quetzaltenango: Diócesis de Quetzaltenango, 1994-1996; 1 item
    - no.1, 6th edition, 1995; 1 item
    - no.2, 4th edition, 1994; 1 item
    - no.3, 4th edition, 1996; 1 item
    - no.4, 4th edition, 1995; 1 item
    - no.5, undated; 1 item